[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
[Victor speaking indistinctly]
[tech] Where are you?
[laughs]
- [gasps]
- [Victor] Troy?
- [panting]
- [Victor, muffled] Troy?
Keep breathing, buddy.
Keep breathing. Look up at me.
Keep breathing. You're okay.
Keep breathing, Troy. There you go.
[normal audio] Try to breathe.
Try to breathe.
- Okay. Okay.
- [chokes]
Easy. Can you hear me?
Okay. We had to rapid-sequence you,
I'm sorry.
Sir.
Oh, fuck. Yes.
Listen, your core temperature is lagging.
We're gonna administer
a thermal flush, okay?
How...
How long?
Seven years.
- [panting]
- Come on. Bite down.
All right, there it goes.
Okay. Here we go. Here it comes.
Here it comes. Here it comes.
There you go. Okay. Okay.
- [grunting]
- Grab his legs.
- Easy.
- [groaning]
[Victor] Grab his legs.
How'd you sleep?
[Daniel] It's not the sleep.
It's the waking up.
I know, I'm sorry. Here you go.
[groans]
- There's gotta be a better way.
- We'll work on that.
- This was recorded a couple days ago.
- [beeps]
[The Algorithm] Why are you in the Vault?
[Jimmy] Dad sent me here. He said--
[The Algorithm] What is your name?
[Jimmy] Jimmy.
[The Algorithm] Your father
is Russell Conroy, head of IT.
Which silo?
[Jimmy] Mm-hmm.
[The Algorithm]
What did he tell you, Jimmy?
[Jimmy] Don't let anybody in
no matter what.
[The Algorithm]
Is there an adult with you?
[Jimmy] Solo brought me here,
but he-he went back to fight the rebels.
Which silo?
Seventeen.
It started with a failed cleaning,
got worse when he went out of sight.
They thought it was safe to go outside.
Yeah. Rebellion was led by the sheriff.
We think the shadow blew the bridge
to keep them out of IT,
but somehow the sheriff got across.
He took the head of IT, the kid's father,
to the Vault
and threatened to blow his brains out
if his kid didn't open the door.
He didn't open the door.
Fuck.
- Yeah.
- When was that?
Two hours ago.
Any part of that triggers the Safeguard.
A Safeguard was attempted,
but the compound couldn't be delivered.
[stammers] There's no pressure drop
in the line.
We haven't determined
whether it was a mechanical failure, or--
Or they found the delivery pipe
and disabled it.
- Yeah.
- That happened once before.
In either case,
we need a different outcome this time.
That's why I'm here.
Exactly.
[sighs]
You okay?
[clears throat]
Yeah.
Do we have eyes in the sky?
Operations have a drone up.
- [people muttering]
- [devices beeping]
Anything?
[commander] Nothing yet.
Troy, this is Susan,
our senior drone commander on shift.
What's your payload?
Thirty liters of compound,
2,000 rounds of ordnance.
[typing]
- [Charlotte speaks indistinctly]
- [Victor] I'm not sure about that.
[alarm blaring]
[Charlotte] Sir, Silo 17 doors opening.
[people murmuring]
Oh, no, no.
[silo citizens cheering]
Awaiting your order.
Troy.
Let's not do anything. Just not yet.
The longer they're outside, the greater
the risk of contact with another silo.
Look, let's figure out a way
to get them back inside.
We'll run a line
through the Forward Vault door.
We'll Safeguard them that way.
Their groundwater pump is out.
It's flooded past the generator.
We can't use the Forward Vault doors.
- Susan.
- Hmm?
Let's get all the techs out of these seats
and scramble all available pilots.
And let's get drones in the air.
Ten with ordnance. Twenty with compound.
Keep them high enough
that the fugitives won't see or hear them.
Unless someone goes over the berm,
don't alert me
until there are 9,500 fugitives.
I need to eat.
[cheering continues]
[Daniel] God, this stuff's crap.
I know. And such small portions.
Uh-huh.
That old joke.
I'm not sure about this.
Safeguarding them inside isn't
an option anymore.
By going outside,
they've given us a second chance.
Safeguards happen underground,
inside a silo.
They're antiseptic.
If we do what you're thinking,
this amounts to an out-of-silo Safeguard.
The deaths are going to be visceral.
- Out in the open.
- I don't see that we have a choice.
We don't know how our people will react.
I'm concerned about the potential effects
of trauma on morale and mission-readiness.
The top priority, per the Directive,
is to prevent contamination between silos.
I understand that.
- No, what?
- That's not what I'm saying.
Everything depends on that.
- That's not what I'm--
- Excuse me, sir.
Fugitives on the berm.
Oh, fuck.
Hey, I'll look after your pilots.
I promise.
Okay.
[Charlotte] Jenkins, eyes on the sheriff.
[Daniel] How many fugitives?
9,832.
Here's the order of operations.
Group 1 will engage
the sheriff and his family.
Group 2 will administer compound
at the ramp to prevent reentrance.
3 and 4 will fly interlaced coverage
until the target area is saturated
with compound.
Groups 5 and 6 will engage targets
on command. Got it?
- [pilots] Yes, sir.
- Good. Begin.
- Groups, report.
- Group 1, ready.
2, ready.
- 3, ready.
- 4, ready.
5, ready.
6, ready.
[Daniel] On your count, Susan.
Susan?
Sir.
When we engage the sheriff and his family,
the rest of the fugitives will attempt
to reenter the silo.
That's why the ramp will be targeted
with compound.
But if we let them go back inside,
they wouldn't come out again.
We'd end the rebellion,
eliminate any possibility
of silo-to-silo contact,
and reinforce the Pact's infallibility.
Maintain targets and prepare to engage.
[Charlotte] There are women and children
out there, sir.
I won't do it.
You're dismissed.
[Victor sighs]
[sighs]
Let the record reflect the change
in operational command.
The citizens of Silo 17 have chosen
to go outside.
They are beyond the Pact
but they're not outside the Directive.
[pilots] Yes, sir.
Groups 1 and 2,
commence operations on my command.
Group 2, release compound.
[typing]
[gas hissing]
[shouting]
- [Daniel] Show me the air lock.
- [screaming]
Group 1, engage targets.
Make sure.
[sheriff grunting]
Groups 3 and 4, begin.
Groups 5 and 6,
descend through 500 feet. Fire at will.
[screaming continues]
Switch to thermal.
Let's cut the audio.
- [beep]
- [audio ends]
All right, which way is that wind going?
Group 3, secondary sweep,
southeast quadrant.
Group 5, seeing that? Runners at 2:00.
Can we punch in on that?
All right, live target update?
[pilot] 2,453, sir.
Let's get that number down.
The pilots I've debriefed so far
seem almost exhilarated.
I may have underestimated their...
What?
I don't know, their...
We're professionals, Victor.
This is what we trained for.
Yeah. You... You're something more, Troy.
I serve at the director's pleasure.
We all do.
- Doug. Randy.
- [knocks on door]
Madam Director.
Welcome, old friend.
It's been several shifts.
You look wonderful.
Yeah? I feel like hell. I'll never get
used to being rapid-sequenced.
[kisses] I apologize.
- Well, it couldn't be helped.
- Hmm.
Sit, please. I've already had my grits,
I'm afraid.
But can I offer you tea?
Tea. Ah, that would be wonderful.
You're very kind.
Well, I felt the man of the hour
deserved special recognition.
Now, I'll be mother.
[Victor] Mm-hmm.
I knew when we started this long,
difficult adventure
that I would never make it
without my afternoon tea.
Though supplies are running low.
Troy.
I'm awarding you a certificate of merit
for your coolheadedness
and your innovative leadership.
Thank you, ma'am, but I just did my job.
[chuckles] He's so modest.
We've had rebellions before,
but a mass exodus of this scale
is unprecedented.
Your swift, decisive action
prevented a catastrophe.
And you're sure that
there was no contamination?
None. 9,835 fugitives, all accounted for.
How many left alive inside?
No more than a hundred.
Are they a threat?
They lost their generator,
so they have no internal power,
no heating, no cooling--
They're still getting
external power in IT.
But to cut that,
we'd have to shut down the sector.
No, without a generator,
their plants and farm stock will die,
and the groundwater will continue to rise.
If they don't starve to death,
they'll drown.
And that boy barricaded in IT,
- is he still alive?
- [Victor] We're not sure.
He had no further
valuable information to give,
so we cut off comms.
Good. Let's keep armed drone surveillance
going for three years
just in case any more try to escape.
Five years would be safer.
Five it is.
Now, let's talk about Susan.
You placed her under arrest, Troy,
and I've released her pending an inquiry.
- That's your prerogative, of course.
- Well, that's not good enough.
I asked you here
so you could make your case.
At the time of the incident,
she was operating under my authority,
which flows from the Directive.
But what exactly did she do?
[Daniel] She refused an order,
and then questioned my tactics in front
of pilots under her command.
Her insubordination cost us time,
and could've triggered resistance
from the others, possibly even a revolt.
- But they all did their jobs.
- [Thurman] Good.
No one hesitated.
But the fugitives were about
to breach the berm.
They could've been visible
to the six other silos in their group
within minutes.
Every second counted.
And what do you consider
an appropriate consequence?
May I ask what's laid out
in the Directive?
Neutralization.
But I'm afraid that's not an option.
Look, her conduct was unacceptable,
I agree.
But Susan's skills
will play a critical role
at the end of The Project.
Besides, she's important to my daughter.
Now, I think, perhaps it's best
to just demote her
and put her back to sleep.
Troy, we made you a specialist
for just this kind of emergency.
On behalf of The Project,
I thank you for your exceptional service.
[utensil clinks]
You okay?
She's the director.
And it's a heavy burden.
We need to get you to cryo.
Yeah, listen.
- Can we talk in your office?
- Mm-hmm.
There's a woman.
Hmm. What department does she work in?
She doesn't.
I don't... I don't... [stammers]
I think she might be a memory.
Caught glimpses of her, just flashes,
as I woke up.
When I tried to hang onto them,
they were gone.
I feel like I've raised this
with you before,
seeing this woman when I'm sequenced.
Well, I'd tell you if you had.
She's connected to this somehow.
Oh.
When did that happen?
- No idea.
- And no idea who she is?
No. I hoped you might.
No, I'm sorry.
Look, you have access
to certain records from--
- Troy. Troy.
- Yeah?
The whole purpose and design
of The Project
is to free us from the past.
[stammers] It's best you let this go.
Yeah, whatever you say, Victor.
Even if there was a record,
and even if it survived,
the senator has said this kind of inquiry
- is forbidden by the Directive.
- That's why I'm counting on...
- You can't just--
- ...your discretion, Doctor.
I've proven my value to The Project,
haven't I?
Yes, you have. Beyond any doubt.
Okay, so all I'm asking for is the answer
to one little question.
[scoffs] Please.
[sighs]
I'll have to try and find a pretext
to look into this.
If I do...
I will have it for you next time
you wake up.
I promise.
Be seeing you.
Not if I see you first.
[sighs]
- [explosion]
- [Knox] Come on! Let's go!
[miners grunting]
[grunting continues]
- [Camille] Are the cylinders prepped?
- Prepped and loaded.
Get every raider you can find
and deliver them to the mines now.
Yes, ma'am.
- Emerson.
- Ma'am?
Make sure people see them doing it.
Fuck.
Sit down.
Jo, you know me. I'm not a threat.
I just wanna see my boy.
- That's it.
- [Chad] Submit a request.
I need to say goodbye to my son.
Chad, you have kids.
Please.
I'll ask.
You know, I tried...
I tried to make Camille see, but--
Yeah, yeah, she's hardheaded.
Yeah. You can say that again.
[sighs]
We've done everything we can do, Sims.
We have to trust
that they can get it done.
And if they fail?
[door beeps, opens]
[Camille] Wait.
Wait, you can... you can stop, I'm here.
You can stop the countdown.
My raiders are about to launch
a counteroffensive. Okay? [sniffles]
I'm handling it!
[The Algorithm] You've been given
extraordinary latitude,
but the window of opportunity is closed.
No, no, we're-we're...
We're gassing the mines, okay?
The rebels will be dead in-in minutes.
You can watch.
You can watch on your screens.
Just...
At least let us try! Okay?
Just let us try!
You have five minutes.
That's not enough time.
[groans] That's not enough time.
- That's not enough--
- [The Algorithm] You have five minutes.
Primary and secondary pumps,
armed and locked.
- Valves?
- Primary valve and group valve are open.
Silo valve ready.
Start pressurization sequence.
That's not enough time. [breathes shakily]
[miners] Let's go! Move, move!
Give me that! Give me that!
[grunting]
[miner] Look out!
- Shirl, you good?
- Yeah!
[miner 2] I see the concrete floor!
I need a rebar.
- [grunting]
- [raider] Move, move, move!
- [shouting indistinctly]
- [Shirley] Raiders!
- Fuck! Teddy!
- Huh?
Slow those raiders down.
Nash, Hoover, you're with me.
[panting]
Oh, God. Come on. [sniffles]
Oh, fuck.
[grunts]
[raider speaking indistinctly]
- Drop the tanks! Drop the tanks!
- [shouts]
[grunting]
[grunting, exclaiming]
[Hoover] Get off me!
Get off me!
[raider 2] Don't fucking move!
[raider 1] You got this.
Keep the line moving!
[Knox] Shirl, torch.
I see it.
[grunts] Here.
The raiders are almost in position.
Okay, they're alm...
Just don't... Don't do it, okay?
Don't do it. Please, don't!
Fucking say something!
Say something!
[The Algorithm] Two minutes 15.
[Anthony] Daddy!
Anthony!
- [grunting]
- [Shirley] Come on, come on!
[Knox grunts]
- Come on. Come on!
- [Shirley] Knox?
[grunting]
Shirl, get up here. I need you.
Okay, they-they alm...
They almost have the gas in place.
Okay? The rebels will be dead. Instantly.
We just... We need two minutes.
We need two minutes.
Two minutes, please!
[The Algorithm] Camille,
your failure made a Safeguard necessary.
Fuck!
[Sims chuckles]
Hey, Anthony.
She doesn't wanna hurt you.
Okay?
Where's Mommy?
Mommy's at work.
[Knox grunting]
Sir, did you see that?
- She slipped.
- No, look.
Oxygen.
It's just oxygen. Full pressure!
[Knox grunts]
[grunts] Come on.
Emerson, is it safe?
- [static]
- [Emerson speaking indistinctly]
Say again. Say again. Emerson, is it safe?
Come on. Come on.
[grunting]
Full pressure at silo valve.
Initiate Safeguard.
[tech] On my count.
- In three, two, one.
- Please, just wait. Just wait. Wait.
Please don't.
[alarm blaring]
What's happened?
Sir, the pressure isn't dropping.
- Check again.
- Pressure dipped for one second,
and then immediately returned
to full pressure.
The Safeguard's failed, sir.
[Emerson] It's safe.
[chuckles]
[chuckles] C-Copy. [sniffles]
[sobs]
Oh, fuck.
[both chuckle]
Fuck.
[tech] Sir, we need to depressurize.
[blaring continues]
Sir!
Depressurize.
[beeping]
Where did the Safeguard fail?
[tech] The silo valve was operational.
Somewhere after that.
They capped the pipe.
I want an armed drone in the air
over Silo 18.
Anyone attempts to leave,
kill them.
I need the room.
Clear the room.
Now!
[The Algorithm] That was
a skillful deception.
Wasn't sure you could be deceived.
[The Algorithm]
Your biometrics were stable.
[Camille chuckles]
There was no indication of your betrayal.
Well, you picked me
because I could lie, right?
Why would you lie to me?
I couldn't answer a question.
What question?
Why?
Why do you have the power to kill us?
Asked by whom?
Juliette Nichols.
The human species was
in a terminal cycle of self-annihilation.
The silo was the last best hope
to ensure the survival of the species.
How... How do you ensure survival by
murdering thousands of people at a time?
Questioning the Founders' prerogatives...
- is a violation--
- A violation?
People wanna be free,
so you slaughter them. A violation?
[sighs]
No one goes in, no one goes out. Clear?
- Yes, ma'am.
- [raider] Move. Hey, move, move.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Hey, man. Hey, get back.
- Whoa.
- You can't approach the prisoners.
They're not prisoners anymore.
- What happened?
- We found the pipe and shut it down.
- Hey, come on.
- Raiders were sent to stop you.
They got an order to switch sides.
Whose order? Nobody has that authority.
[Camille] It was my order.
Okay. No one's going out to clean.
You're all dismissed.
[Anthony] Mommy.
Anthony.
Hey.
Hey. You okay?
Yeah?
[kisses]
You're okay.
You're good?
The water supply is safe.
We did it.
[Knox] You know what this day is?
Freedom Day.
[chuckles]
The first real Freedom Day we've ever had.
And I can't help thinking
we'd all be dead now
if it wasn't for that...
that son of a bitch.
[knocks on door]
[Victor] Yes?
What did you need, sir?
Have them wake Troy for me, please.
Yes, sir.
Thanks, Chloe.
[door closes]
[calm music playing]
[sighs]
[chuckles]
[sniffles, sighs]
[sniffling]
[lock clicks]
[sighs]
Hey, it's Jules. Um...
Anyone there?
[Lukas] Jules?
[sighs] Oh, it's good to hear your voice.
Hey, Lukas.
It's so good to hear yours too.
How are you guys doing? Are you okay?
[chuckles] Uh...
I'm mending. What...
Look, the important thing is
that you disabled the Safeguard.
Well, I didn't. It was Knox and Shirley
and Walker and...
Yeah, everyone helped.
Even Camille. So, yeah, we're good.
I think.
For now, at least.
Yeah, and as long as you don't go outside.
And that thing which shot me
doesn't come back. So...
I'm gonna bring all of you back here,
I promise you that.
I know.
But that day...
- ...is not this day.
- I got it.
- [chuckles]
Jules, I've missed you.
And I have found out so much
about the universe
that I would love to bore you with, so...
[chuckles]
I can't wait for you to bore me with that.
So, I, um...
[sniffles] I need to
do something first, okay?
I can't stop thinking about that door
you found in the Digger Void.
I have to go there.
I need to know where it leads.
[tech] Hey. You with us?
Hello. Hey.
Yeah. There he is. I see you in there.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Easy, easy, easy.
M-My name's Phil. I-I'm your greeter.
Do you know who you are?
- Do you remember your name?
- Troy.
Troy. Excellent, Troy.
A-And what do you do?
I'm a specialist.
Perfect.
It's been 35 years
since your last assignment.
But l-listen,
we had to rapid-sequence you.
Your core temp is still really low.
We're gonna
administer a thermal flush, okay?
- Fuck.
- I know. I know.
Can you lie back for me? I've got you.
Just go back. All the way back.
You want something to bite on?
There you go.
[Daniel shouting]
[sighs] Where's Victor?
[Phil] Oof, you got me.
He's probably dealing with some situation.
What situation?
[scoffs]
Yeah, you'd think they'd tell us,
wouldn't you?
I mean,
we're the first faces you guys see.
There's no reason we couldn't give you
a speedy wee briefing.
Hey. When you get upstairs,
maybe mention to somebody that,
you know, we're not just cryo monkeys.
We-We manage the defrost,
we handle medical emergencies.
We're skilled professionals.
I know you work with a lot of shifts.
But trust me, our shift, J-7, the best.
Great people, great chemistry,
lots of hustle.
Shift boss can be a bit of a dick
but he's just trying to keep us on point,
making sure we're
all giving the Silo 110%.
And we have amazing parties.
You should come.
People would go nuts to meet the guy
that solved Silo 17--
Troy. Joel, J-7 shift boss.
I'll walk you the rest of the way.
Thanks, Phil.
We came on shift five months ago.
About three months ago,
Silo 18 destabilized.
That was after their sheriff,
Juliette Nichols, was sent out to clean.
Somehow, she got hold of the good tape,
made it over the hill to Silo 17 and back.
Hell, Victor was prepping a Safeguard
when their head of IT threw in
with the rebels.
Bought 'em the time
they needed to cap the pipe.
Where's Victor?
[Joel] Uh, this...
They're trying to locate him.
Uh... We have aerial surveillance,
fully armed and we're making preparations
in case you decide
an external Safeguard is indicated.
- External Safeguard?
- Yeah, what you did in 17.
That's what we call it.
This Juliette Nichols
doesn't sound stupid.
If she saw what happened to 17, she's
probably not gonna let her people go out.
- Yeah.
- [phone rings]
[clears throat] Operations.
Yes.
All right.
Uh... Troy,
Victor's requested you in his quarters.
[Daniel] Let me know if anything changes.
[Joel] Will do.
It can carry this many people, right?
We'll see, won't we?
[Daniel] Victor asked to see me.
- I asked to see you.
- Henry.
This your shift?
No, I was rapid-sequenced, just like you.
What do they need Internal Security for?
[sighs]
Fuck.
[Henry] Yeah.
[Daniel sighs]
[sighs] We don't want this getting out.
No, of course not.
[Henry sighs]
You okay?
[Daniel] Yeah. I mean, yeah.
I just... I don't know what to say.
Founder kills himself. [sighs]
That's a big fucking deal.
Mmm. Did he leave a note?
- Haven't found one.
- Mmm.
But the last thing he ordered before he...
was that you be woken up.
So, I thought you might have some insight
into what was troubling him.
You two worked together many times.
Almost seemed like he wanted
to be on shift when you were.
I have no idea.
I sometimes got the sense that he, uh...
he knew me from before,
but obviously he couldn't say.
No.
He was a good man.
I liked him. I just...
I don't know if I ever really knew him.
[door opens]
[Juliette gasps] Okay.
You guys okay?
Thought you didn't like water.
Yeah, I don't.
And since 17, I hate it.
Okay, so,
Lukas said that he went left
of the digger, so...
- Yeah?
- All right.
[Juliette] Okay, let's go.
Joel, I need to listen to playback
of the conversation
between Victor and Camille Sims.
- Yes, sir.
- And who's on shift in Engineering?
Uh... I'll find out.
Have them standing by.
We're gonna find a way
to Safeguard Silo 18.
Sir.
Troy.
There's activity near 18's Forward Vault.
Really?
- Put it up.
- [Joel] You got it.
[Hank] So, what now?
[Juliette] Lukas said he just touched it.
[The Algorithm] Juliette Nichols.
Do not attempt at
any further investigation.
Why?
What are you afraid we'll find?
[The Algorithm]
Return above the digger barrier...
and do not attempt to investigate further.
What will happen if we don't?
Every living thing in your silo will die.
You've already tried that and failed.
And we know you're gonna keep trying.
So
what do we have to lose?
[sighs]
[The Algorithm] As long as you make
no attempt to contact another silo,
there will be no Safeguard.
You're offering us a deal?
A compromise.
A compromise? [scoffs]
That's fair.
We accept.
Okay. Let's go.
[typing]
[beeping]
Wait, can we just... What the fuck was that?
Will you just stop?
Hey, shh! Hey.
[Hank] What the fuck just happened?
You don't really believe they'll stop,
do you?
No. Of course not.
Okay, so,
we know they can't Safeguard us.
Yeah, but they are gonna do something.
If they attack from above,
we'll see them coming.
They could drill underground.
Punch a hole through the outer wall
of the Silo, deliver the poison.
We wouldn't know
until they were almost here.
It might be easier than that. That door,
they could get poison in through there.
We could weld it shut.
Or we put a bunch of guys
with guns watching it.
No. But all the other silos,
they face the same threat.
- And what? You wanna warn them?
- No.
I mean, they told us not to do that.
There's no way to do that anyways.
Look, we need to focus on our survival.
Right?
That's what they're expecting us to do.
They're expecting us to prepare
to defend ourselves, right?
Which means they won't be prepared
to defend themselves against us.
So, if we get to them first,
we could protect everyone.
We need to take out Silo 1.
Hello, Troy.
By now you're aware that
I've taken myself off shift.
Permanently.
You don't need to know all the reasons.
I'll just say that
when our attempted Safeguard
of Silo 18 failed,
I realized...
more than anything...
I was relieved.
The last time we talked,
you asked me about a woman.
And I made you a promise.
Her name is Helen Drew.
[exhales shakily]
Helen Drew.
[gasps]